CHAPTER 10. The Lobster quadrile The Mock Turtle sighed deeply, and drew
the back of one flapper across his eyes.
He looked at Alice, and tried to speak, but for a minute or two Saabs choked his voice.
“Same as if he had a bone in his throat,” said the Griffin and it set to work
shaking him and punching him in the back.
At last the Mock Turtle recovered his voice, and, with tears running down his
cheeks, he went on again:— “You may not have lived much under the
sea—” (“I haven’t,” said Alice)—“ )—“and perhaps you were never even introduced to a lobster—”
(Alice began to say “I once tasted—” but checked herself hastily, and said “No, never”)
“—so you can have no idea what a delightful thing a Lobster quadril is!”
“No, indeed,” said Alice. “What sort of a dance is it?” “Why,” said the Griffin you
first form into a line along the seizure pool lines!” cried the Mock Turtle. “Seals,
turtles, salmon, and so on; then, when you’ve cleared all the jellyfish out of the way—”
That generally takes some time,” interrupted the Griffin you Advanced
twice—” “Each with a lobster as a partner!” cried the Griffin Of course,” the Mock
Turtle said: “advance twice, set to partners—” “—change lobsters, and retire in
the same order,” continued the Griffin Then, you know,” the Mock Turtle went on,
“you throw the—” “The lobsters!” shouted the Griffin with a bound into
the air. “—as far out to sea as you can—” “Swim after them!”
screamed the Griffin Turn a somersault in the sea!” cried the Mock Turtle,
capering wildly about. “Change lobsters again!” yelled the Griffin at the top of its
voice. “Back to land again, and that’s all the first figure,”
said the Mock Turtle, suddenly dropping his voice; and the two creatures, who had
been jumping about like mad things all this time, sat down again very sadly and
quietly, and looked at Alice.
“It must be a very pretty dance,” said Alice timidly. “Would you like to
see a little of it?” said the Mock Turtle. “Very much indeed,” said Alice.
“Come, let’s try the first figure!” said the Mock Turtle to the Griffin We
can do without lobsters, you know. Which shall sing?” “Oh, you sing,” said the Griffin I’ve
forgotten the words.” So they began solemnly dancing round and round Alice,
every now and then treading on her toes when they passed too close, and waving
their Four Paws to mark the time, while the Mock Turtle sang this, very slowly and sadly:—
“Will you walk a little faster instead of witting to a snail. “There’s a purpose
close behind us, and he’s treading on my tail. See how eagerly the lobsters and
the turtles all advance! They are waiting on the shingle— —will you come and join the dance?
Will you, won’t you, will you, won’t you,
will you join the dance? Will you, won’t
you, will you, won’t you, won’t you join the dance? “You can really have no notion
how delightful it will be When they take us up and throw us, with the lobsters, out
to sea!” But the snail replied “Too far, too fast and the evil look a scans Said he
thanked the witting kindly, but he would not join the dance.
Would not, could not, would not, could not, would not join the dance. Would not, could
not, would not, could not, could not join the dance. “What matters it how far we go?”
his scaly friend replied. “There is another sure you know, upon the other
side. The further off from England the nearest to France and turn that pale,
beloved snail, but come and join the dance. Will you want you, will you want
you, will you join the dance? Will you,
won’t you, will you, won’t you, won’t you join the dance?”
“Thank you, it’s a very interesting dance to watch,” said Alice, feeling very glad
that it was over at last: “and I do so like that curious song about the whiting!”
“Oh, as to the whiting,” said the Mock Turtle, “they— —you’ve you've seen them, of
course?” “Yes,” said Alice, “I’ve often seen them at dinner she checked herself hastily.
“I don’t know where din may be,” said the Mock Turtle, “but have you seen them so
often, of course you know what they’re like.” “I believe so,” Alice replied thoughtfully.
“They have their tails in their mouths— —and they’re all over crumbs.”
“You’re wrong about the crumbs,” said the Mock Turtle: “crumbs would all wash off in
the sea. But they have their tails in their mouths; and the reason is—” here the
Mock Turtle yawned and shut his eyes.—“ .—“Tell her about the reason and all that,”
he said to the Griffin The reason is,” said the Griffin that they would go with
the lobsters to the dance. So they got thrown out to sea.
So they had to fall a long way.
So they got their tails fast in their mouths. So they couldn’t get them out again.
That’s all.” “Thank you,” said Alice, “it’s very interesting.
I never knew so much about a whiting before.” “I can tell you more than that, if you
like,” said the Griffin Do you know why it’s cold a whiting?”
“I never thought about it,” said Alice.
“Why?” It does the boots and the shoes the Griffin replied very solemnly.
Alice was thoroughly puzzled.
“Does the boots and the shoes!” she repeated in a Wandering tone.
“Why, what are your shoes done with?” said the Griffin I mean, what makes them so shiny
Alison looked down at them, and considered a little before she gave her answer.
“They’re done with blacking, I believe.” “Boots and shoes under the sea,” the
Griffin went on in a deep voice, “are done with a whiting.
Now you know.” “And what are they made of?” Alice asked in
a tone of great curiosity souls and eels, of course,” the Griffin replied rather
impatiently: “any shrimp could have told you that.” “If I’d been the whiting,” said Alice, whose
thoughts were still running on the song, “I’d have said to the porpoise,
‘Keep back, please: we don’t want you with us!’” “They were obliged to have him with them,”
the Mock Turtle said: “no wise fish would go anywhere without a porpoise.”
“Wouldn’t it really?” said Alice in a tone of great surprise. “Of course not,” said the
Mock Turtle: “why, if a fish came to me and
told me he was going on a journey, I should say ‘With what porpoise?’”
“Don’t you mean ‘purpose’?” said Alice.
“I mean what I say,” the Mock Turtle replied in an offended tone.
And the Griffin added “Come, let’s hear some of your adventures.” “I
could tell you my adventures— —beginning from this morning,” said Alice a little timidly:
“but it’s no use going back to yesterday, because I was a different person then.”
“Explain all that,” said the Mock Turtle.
“No, no! The adventures first,” said the Griffin in an impatient tone:
“explanations take such a dreadful time.” So Alice began telling them her
adventures from the time when she first saw the White Rabbit.
She was a little nervous about it just at first, the two creatures got so close to her,
one on each side, and opened their eyes and mouth so very wide,
but she gained courage as she went on.
Her listeners were perfectly quiet till she got to the part about her repeating
You are old, Father William to the Caterpillar, and the words all coming different,
and then the Mock Turtle drew a long breath, and said very curious.” “It’s all
about as curious as it can be,” said the Griffin It all came different!”
the Mock Turtle repeated thoughtfully. “I should like to hear her try and repeat
something now. Tell her to begin.” He looked at the Griffin as if he
thought it had some kind of authority over Alice.
“Stand up and repeat Tis the voice of the sluggard said the Griffin
How the creatures order one about, and make one repeat lessons!” thought Alice; “I
might as well be at school at once.” However, she got up, and began to repeat
it, but her head was so full of the Lobster quadrile that she hardly knew
what she was saying, and the words came very queer indeed:— “’Tis the voice of the
Lobster; I heard him declare, “You have backed me to brown, I must sugar my hair.”
As a duck with its eyelids, so he with his nose Trims his belt and his buttons,
and turns out his toes That’s different from what I used to say
when I was a child,” said the Griffin Well, I never heard it before,” said the Mock
Turtle; “but it sounds uncommon nonsense.” Alice said nothing;
she had sat down with her face in her hands, wondering if anything would ever
happen in a natural way again. “I should like to have it explained,” said the Mock
Turtle. “She can’t explain it,” said the Griffin hastily. “Go on with the next verse
what about his toes?” the Mock Turtle persisted. “How could he turn them out
with his nose, you know?” “It’s the first position in dancing.”
Alice said; but was dreadfully puzzled by the whole thing, and longed to change the subject.
“Go on with the next verse,” the Griffin repeated impatiently: “it begins I passed by his garden
Alice did not dare to disobey, though she felt sure it would all come wrong, and
she went on in a trembling voice I'd passed by his garden, and marked, with
one eye, How the Owl and the Panther were sharing a pie
The Panther took pie crust and gravy, and meat, While the Owl had the dish as its
share of the treat.
When the pie was all finished, the Owl, as a boon, Was kindly permitted to pocket the spoon:
While the Panther received knife and fork with a growl, And concluded the
banquet—] “What is the use of repeating all that stuff,”
the Mock Turtle interrupted, “if you don’t
explain it as you go on? It’s by far the most confusing thing I ever heard!”
“Yes, I think you’d better leave off,” said the Griffin and Alice was only too glad
to do so. “Shall we try another figure of the Lobster quadrile the Griffin went on.
“Or would you like the Mock Turtle to sing you a song?”
“Oh, a song, please, if the Mock Turtle would be so kind,” Alice replied, so eagerly that the
Griffin said, in a rather offended tone No accounting for tastes!
Sing her Turtle Soup will you, old fellow?” The Mock Turtle sighed deeply, and began,
in a voice sometimes choked with sobs, to sing this:— “Beautiful Soup, so rich and green wading
in a hot touring Who for such dainties would not stoop? Soup of the evening,
beautiful Soup! Soup of the evening, beautiful Soup beautiful soup beautiful soup
soup of the evening, Beautiful, beautiful Soup! “Beautiful Soup! Who cares for a fish,
Game, or any other dish? Who would not give all else for two penny worth only a
beautiful Soup penny worth only a beautiful Soup beautiful soup beautiful soup
soup of the evening, Beautiful beautiful SOUP course again!”
cried the Griffin and the Mock Turtle had just begun to repeat it, when a cry
of “The trials beginning!” was heard in the distance. “Come on!” cried
the Griffin and, taking Alice by the hand, it hurried off, without waiting for the
end of the song.
“What trial is it?” Alice panted as she ran; but the Griffin only answered “Come on!”
and ran the faster, while more and more faintly came, carried on the breeze that
followed them, the melancholy words soup of the evening, Beautiful, beautiful Soup